Khoa Henry Nguyen

Software Engineer

Cell:414-306-4982 | Email: knguyen041802@gmail.com | Linkedin: Khoa-Henry-Nguyen | GitHub: GitHub

About Me

Summary: Experienced Front-end Developer with a robust skill set encompassing application development, web design, cloud computing, and IT support. Recognized for a meticulous attention to detail, self-driven initiative, and unwavering reliability, I consistently deliver as a dedicated and diligent front-end/React developer.

Skills: React JS, Git, AWS, TypeScript, JavaScript, Jest, HTML/CSS, Scrum, SQL.

CERTIFICATION: AWS - Cloud Practitioner

EXPERIENCE

American Family Insurance — Application Development Engineer

November 2020 - PRESENT

- Developed AMFAM's digital sales platform for auto to retire AMFAM's old auto sales tool (Highest Priority).
- Constructed the integration of The General insurance to be part of the sales tool when a user is not qualified.
- Created the payment details page, sign documents page, premium summary page, payment options page, vin validation feature, and city/state prefill feature.
- Incorporated multiple products (auto, home, etc.) in the application for bundling features.
- Identified and corrected software and data errors to support current development.
- Optimized the Digital-Sales Auto application by employing best coding practices to combine multiple repositories.
- Increased performance of the Digital-Sales Auto by implementing efficient data structures.

i.c. Stars Milwaukee - Software Developer

July 2020 - November 2020

- Initialized the process of designing a wireframe, and a workflow model, and using React.js to build a mobile app. (Paylocity App)
- Collaborated with the team and end-users to identify requirements, designs, and solutions for our client, Paylocity. Reimagine the current Paylocity App to a modern application that engages the user and builds a community for all users.
- Communicated with professionals in the IT field, project managers, CIOs, etc.

Tier1 Gaming Lounge — General Manager & IT Technician

May 2016 - September 2020

- Redesigned and maintained our existing website using Weebly. (https://www.tierlgl.com)
- Helped configure server computers and client computers, 40+ computers.
- Troubleshoot Windows and gaming center software on client computers.
- Worked with a team of 4 to plan and run events and tournaments.
- Helped to set up the client's computer hardware.

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee — Computer Science